<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speeches on Future of Australian Mining</title>
    <link>/categories/speeches/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speeches on Future of Australian Mining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/speeches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Science, Opportunity and Profit - Speech to 2018 AMEC Conference</title>
      <link>/2018/06/13/2018-06-213-amec-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/13/2018-06-213-amec-2018/</guid>
      <description>Next year will mark the 160th anniversary of one of the first major Australian mineral finds. Back then, on 17 December 1859, a stockman noticed a wombat kicking up some strange, green-looking pebbles. He reported the sighting to his boss Walter Watson Hughes, a sea captain turned pastoralist.1
His find eventually became the Wallaroo copper mine and this mine, along with other discoveries of copper, helped save the then fledgling colony of South Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Long Mining Boom - Address to the National Press Club</title>
      <link>/2018/03/28/nat-press-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/28/nat-press-club/</guid>
      <description>I want to thank the National Press Club for this opportunity and thank them for co-hosting this event with the National Rural Press Club. Thanks to their President Colin Bettles and his committee for helping to make this happen. We need more voices from the regions heard in Canberra.
I am here to talk about rocks and hydrocarbons but I am going to start talking about people.
First, Alicia. I met Alicia on a visit to the Peak Downs coal mine in Central Queensland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining has never been more important - Speech to the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, Washington DC</title>
      <link>/2018/03/09/csis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/09/csis/</guid>
      <description>The German historian Alexander Dermandt once compiled 210 reasons for the fall of the Roman Empire. One of the 210 reasons was the depletion of its mineral resources.1
Even though I am a bit of a Roman history buff, I do not know whether Alexander was right or wrong. Whatever happened back then, our modern society is more reliant on the cheap availability of mineral resources than Rome.
Take the smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We now need more gas production - Speech to the Australian Domestic Outlook Conference 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/03/02/gas-outlook-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/02/gas-outlook-2018/</guid>
      <description>Last year when I spoke to this conference, I did so in the context of very high domestic gas prices. At the time I noted that the domestic price of gas in Adelaide was $14 / GJ compared to a price of $11 / GJ in Japan.
I said last year that the Australian Government was committed to protecting jobs and that we would act if necessary, and we have acted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>