<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Future of Australian Mining</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Future of Australian Mining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finalising the National Resources Statement</title>
      <link>/2018/12/12/finalising-the-national-resources-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/12/finalising-the-national-resources-statement/</guid>
      <description>Speech to the Melbourne Mining ClubPerhaps the most famous history of the Australian resources sector, written by Geoffrey Blainey, is subtitled “The rush that never ended”. The first edition of that book was written 55 years ago, and I don’t think the rush has ended yet.
Since the mid 2000s, employment, production and tax revenues in and from the resources sector have all more than doubled, and wages in the resources sector have increased by more than 70 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To get cheaper gas we need to develop more gas</title>
      <link>/2018/07/16/gas-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/16/gas-supply/</guid>
      <description>Nobody had much heard of the Gas Supply Opportunities Outlook or the (“GSOO”) before, but the version released in March last year changed the government’s approach to gas markets almost overnight. That report warned that in 2018 southern Australia was headed for a 10 to 54 petajoules gas shortage.1
Within a week Australia’s gas industry was called to Canberra to meet with the Prime Minister, and other relevant Ministers, to discuss how to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The coal era is not coming to an end</title>
      <link>/2018/06/22/coal-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/22/coal-era/</guid>
      <description>When the Hazelwood power station shut last year the Australian Conservation Foundation claimed that its closure was a signal that “the era of polluting coal is coming to an end.”1
In its last full year of operation, the Hazelwood power station generated 10 terawatt hours of coal power.2 In the last year, coal fired power generation has increased in the Asia Pacific region by 330 terawatt hours. So, in effect, in just one year, the Asian region has brought online the equivalent of 33 Hazelwoods - while we shut one coal fired power station in Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science, Opportunity and Profit - Speech to 2018 AMEC Conference</title>
      <link>/2018/06/13/2018-06-213-amec-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/13/2018-06-213-amec-2018/</guid>
      <description>Next year will mark the 160th anniversary of one of the first major Australian mineral finds. Back then, on 17 December 1859, a stockman noticed a wombat kicking up some strange, green-looking pebbles. He reported the sighting to his boss Walter Watson Hughes, a sea captain turned pastoralist.1
His find eventually became the Wallaroo copper mine and this mine, along with other discoveries of copper, helped save the then fledgling colony of South Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Long Mining Boom - Address to the National Press Club</title>
      <link>/2018/03/28/nat-press-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/28/nat-press-club/</guid>
      <description>I want to thank the National Press Club for this opportunity and thank them for co-hosting this event with the National Rural Press Club. Thanks to their President Colin Bettles and his committee for helping to make this happen. We need more voices from the regions heard in Canberra.
I am here to talk about rocks and hydrocarbons but I am going to start talking about people.
First, Alicia. I met Alicia on a visit to the Peak Downs coal mine in Central Queensland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining has never been more important - Speech to the Centre for Strategic and International Studies, Washington DC</title>
      <link>/2018/03/09/csis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/09/csis/</guid>
      <description>The German historian Alexander Dermandt once compiled 210 reasons for the fall of the Roman Empire. One of the 210 reasons was the depletion of its mineral resources.1
Even though I am a bit of a Roman history buff, I do not know whether Alexander was right or wrong. Whatever happened back then, our modern society is more reliant on the cheap availability of mineral resources than Rome.
Take the smartphone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We now need more gas production - Speech to the Australian Domestic Outlook Conference 2018</title>
      <link>/2018/03/02/gas-outlook-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/02/gas-outlook-2018/</guid>
      <description>Last year when I spoke to this conference, I did so in the context of very high domestic gas prices. At the time I noted that the domestic price of gas in Adelaide was $14 / GJ compared to a price of $11 / GJ in Japan.
I said last year that the Australian Government was committed to protecting jobs and that we would act if necessary, and we have acted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>